<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop">
  <id>org.gnome.Contacts.Devel.desktop</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-2.0-or-later</project_license>
  <name>Contacts</name>
  <name xml:lang="zh_TW">聯絡人</name>
  <name xml:lang="zh_HK">聯絡人</name>
  <name xml:lang="zh_CN">联系人</name>
  <name xml:lang="vi">Danh bạ</name>
  <name xml:lang="uk">Контакти</name>
  <name xml:lang="ug">ئالاقەداشلار</name>
  <name xml:lang="tr">Kişiler</name>
  <name xml:lang="th">สมุดผู้ติดต่อ</name>
  <name xml:lang="tg">Тамосҳо</name>
  <name xml:lang="te">పరిచయాలు</name>
  <name xml:lang="ta">தொடர்புகள்</name>
  <name xml:lang="sv">Kontakter</name>
  <name xml:lang="sr@latin">Kontakti</name>
  <name xml:lang="sr">Контакти</name>
  <name xml:lang="sl">Stiki</name>
  <name xml:lang="sk">Kontakty</name>
  <name xml:lang="ru">Контакты</name>
  <name xml:lang="ro">Contacte</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt_BR">Contatos</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt">Contactos</name>
  <name xml:lang="pl">Kontakty</name>
  <name xml:lang="pa">ਸੰਪਰਕ</name>
  <name xml:lang="or">ସମ୍ପର୍କଗୁଡ଼ିକ</name>
  <name xml:lang="oc">Contactes</name>
  <name xml:lang="nl">Contacten</name>
  <name xml:lang="ne">सम्पर्कहरू</name>
  <name xml:lang="nb">Kontakter</name>
  <name xml:lang="mr">संपर्क</name>
  <name xml:lang="ml">സമ്പര്‍ക്കങ്ങള്‍</name>
  <name xml:lang="mk">Контакти</name>
  <name xml:lang="mjw">Contacts</name>
  <name xml:lang="lv">Kontakti</name>
  <name xml:lang="lt">Kontaktai</name>
  <name xml:lang="ko">연락처</name>
  <name xml:lang="kn">ಕಾಂಟ್ಯಾಕ್ಟ್ಸ್‌</name>
  <name xml:lang="kk">Контакттар</name>
  <name xml:lang="ja">連絡先</name>
  <name xml:lang="it">Contatti</name>
  <name xml:lang="is">Tengiliðir</name>
  <name xml:lang="id">Kontak</name>
  <name xml:lang="hu">Névjegyek</name>
  <name xml:lang="hr">Kontakti</name>
  <name xml:lang="hi">संपर्क</name>
  <name xml:lang="he">אנשי קשר</name>
  <name xml:lang="gu">સંપર્કો</name>
  <name xml:lang="gl">Contactos</name>
  <name xml:lang="gd">Luchd-aithne</name>
  <name xml:lang="ga">Teagmhálacha</name>
  <name xml:lang="fur">Contats</name>
  <name xml:lang="fr">Contacts</name>
  <name xml:lang="fi">Yhteystiedot</name>
  <name xml:lang="fa">آشنایان</name>
  <name xml:lang="eu">Kontaktuak</name>
  <name xml:lang="et">Kontaktid</name>
  <name xml:lang="es">Contactos</name>
  <name xml:lang="eo">Kontaktaro</name>
  <name xml:lang="en_GB">Contacts</name>
  <name xml:lang="en_CA">Contacts</name>
  <name xml:lang="el">Επαφές</name>
  <name xml:lang="de">Kontakte</name>
  <name xml:lang="da">Kontakter</name>
  <name xml:lang="cs">Kontakty</name>
  <name xml:lang="ca@valencia">Contactes</name>
  <name xml:lang="ca">Contactes</name>
  <name xml:lang="bs">Kontakti</name>
  <name xml:lang="bn_IN">পরিচিতি-সমূহ</name>
  <name xml:lang="be">Кантакты</name>
  <name xml:lang="ast">Contautos</name>
  <name xml:lang="as">পৰিচয়সমূহ</name>
  <name xml:lang="ar">المتراسلين</name>
  <name xml:lang="af">Kontakte</name>
  <summary>A contacts manager for GNOME</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="zh_TW">GNOME 的聯絡人管理員</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="zh_HK">GNOME 的聯絡人管理程式</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="zh_CN">GNOME 的联系人管理工具</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="vi">Bộ quản lý danh bạ dành cho GNOME</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="uk">Керування контактами для GNOME</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="tr">GNOME için Adres Defteri Yöneticisi</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="th">โปรแกรมจัดการสมุดผู้ติดต่อสำหรับ GNOME</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="tg">Мудири тамосҳо барои GNOME</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="te">గ్నోమ్ కొరకు ఒక పరిచయాల నిర్వాహిక</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ta">GNOME க்கான தொடர்பு நிர்வாகி</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sv">En kontakthanterare för GNOME</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sr@latin">Gnomov upravnik kontaktima</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sr">Гномов управник контактима</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sl">Upravljalnik stikov namizja GNOME</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sk">Správca kontaktov prostredia GNOME</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ru">Менеджер контактов для GNOME</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ro">Un manager de contacte pentru GNOME</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt_BR">Um gerenciador de contatos para o GNOME</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt">Um gestor de contactos para o GNOME</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pl">Menedżer kontaktów dla środowiska GNOME</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pa">ਗਨੋਮ ਲਈ ਸੰਪਰਕ ਮੈਨੇਜਰ</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="or">GNOME ପାଇଁ ଏକ ସମ୍ପର୍କ ପରିଚାଳକ</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="oc">Un gestionari de contactes per GNOME</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nl">Contactenbeheer voor de Gnome-werkomgeving</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ne">जिनोमको लागि एक समपर्क प्रबन्धक</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nb">Håndtering av kontakter for GNOME</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="mr">GNOME करिता संपर्क व्यवस्थापन</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="mjw">A contacts manager for GNOME</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="lv">GNOME kontaktu pārvaldnieks</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="lt">GNOME kontaktų tvarkytuvė</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ko">그놈용 연락처 관리자</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="kn">GNOME ಗಾಗಿನ ಸಂಪರ್ಕವಿಳಾಸದ ವ್ಯವಸ್ಥಾಪನೆ</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="kk">GNOME үшін контакттарды басқарушысы</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ja">GNOME の連絡先管理ツール</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="it">Un gestore di contatti per GNOME</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="is">Tengiliðastjórnun fyrir GNOME</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="id">Manajer kontak untuk GNOME</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="hu">Egy névjegykezelő a GNOME-hoz</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="hr">Upravitelj kontaktima za GNOME</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="hi">गनोम के लिए संपर्क प्रबंधक</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="he">מנהל אנשי קשר עבור GNOME</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="gu">GNOME માટે સંપર્ક સંચાલક</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="gl">Un xestor de contactos para GNOME</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="gd">Manaidsear luchd-aithne airson GNOME</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fur">Un gjestôr contats par GNOME</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fr">Un gestionnaire de contacts pour GNOME</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fi">Yhteystietojen hallinta Gnomelle</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fa">یک مدیریت آشنایان برای گنوم</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="eu">Kontaktuen kudeatzailea GNOMErako</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="es">Un gestor de contactos para GNOME</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="eo">Kontakto-mastrumilo por GNOME</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="en_GB">A contacts manager for GNOME</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="el">Ένας διαχειριστής επαφών του GNOME.</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="de">Eine Kontaktverwaltung für GNOME</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="da">En kontaktpersonhåndtering til GNOME</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="cs">Správa kontaktů pro GNOME</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ca@valencia">Un gestor de contactes per al GNOME</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ca">Un gestor de contactes per al GNOME</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="bs">Kontakt upravitelj za GNOME</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="bn_IN">GNOME-এর জন্য একটি পরিচিতি ব্যবস্থাপক</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="be">Кіраўнік кантактаў для GNOME</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="as">GNOME ৰ বাবে এটা পৰিচয় ব্যৱস্থাপক</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ar">مدير متراسلين لجنوم</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      Contacts keeps and organize your contacts information. You can create,
      edit, delete and link together pieces of information about your contacts.
      Contacts aggregates the details from all your sources providing a
      centralized place for managing your contacts.
    </p>
    <p xml:lang="zh_TW">《聯絡人》會保存並管理您的聯絡人資訊。您可以建立、編輯、刪除與連結關於您的聯絡人的一些資訊。《聯絡人》聯合您所有來源的詳細資料，以提供一個集中管理您的聯絡人的地方。</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh_HK">Contacts 保存並管理你的聯絡人資訊。你可以建立、編輯、刪除與連結關於你的聯絡人的一些資訊。Contacts 聯合你所有來源的詳細資料，以提供一個集中管理你的聯絡人的地方。</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh_CN">联系人可以保存和管理您的联系人信息。您可以创建、编辑、删除联系人，以及将您联系人的各种信息归拢在一起。联系人可以整合各方面的联系人资料，集中管理您的联系人。</p>
    <p xml:lang="vi">Sổ danh bạ giúp bạn lưu giữ và tổ chức các liên hệ của mình. Bạn có thể tạo, sửa, xóa và liên kết các liên lạc của mình thành nhóm. Các liên lạc được tập hợp từ mọi nguồn và cung cấp cho bạn một nơi tập trung để quản lý các liên lạc của mình.</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">Контакти зберігають і впорядковують вашу контактну інформацію. Можете створювати, редагувати і сполучати інформацію про ваші контакти. Контакти збирають подробиці з усіх джерел в одне ціле, надаючи центральне місце для організування ваших контактів.</p>
    <p xml:lang="tr">Kişiler uygulaması kişilerinizin bilgilerini saklar ve düzenler. Kişileriniz hakkındaki bilgileri oluşturabilir, düzenleyebilir, silebilir ve birbirine bağlayabilirsiniz. Kişiler uygulaması tüm kaynaklarınızdaki bilgileri birleştirerek tek bir yerden yönetmenize olanak sağlar.</p>
    <p xml:lang="th">สมุดผู้ติดต่อจะเก็บและจัดการข้อมูลผู้ติดต่อของคุณ คุณสามารถสร้าง, แก้ไข, ลบ, และเชื่อมโยงข้อมูลส่วนต่างๆ ของผู้ติดต่อของคุณเข้าด้วยกัน สมุดผู้ติดต่อรวบรวมรายละเอียดจากแหล่งทั้งหมดของคุณให้มารวมศูนย์ที่แห่งเดียว เพื่อการจัดการผู้ติดต่อของคุณ</p>
    <p xml:lang="tg">Барномаи "Тамосҳо" маълумоти тамосҳои шуморо нигоҳ медорад ва мураттаб мекунад. Шумо метавонед қисмҳои маълумотро оид ба тамосҳои худ эҷод, таҳрир, нест ва пайваст кунед. Барномаи "Тамосҳо" тафсилотро аз ҳамаи манбаҳои шумо ҷамъ карда ҷои марказиро барои идоракунии тамосҳои шумо таъмин менамояд.</p>
    <p xml:lang="te">పరిచయాలు మీ పరిచయాల సమాచారం నిర్వహించును. మీ పరిచయాలకు సంబందించిన సమాచారం సృష్టించవచ్చు, సరికూర్చవచ్చు, తొలగించవచ్చు. పరిచయాలు మీ అన్ని మూలాల నుండి వచ్చు పరిచయ సమాచారంను కేంద్రీయంగా నిర్వహించును.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ta">Contacts உங்கள் தொடர்புகளைப் பற்றிய தகவல்களை சேகரித்து ஒழுங்கமைத்து வைக்கிறது. இதைக் கொண்டு நீங்கள் உங்கள் தொடர்புகளின் தகவல்கள் பலவற்றை உருவாக்கவும் திருத்தவும் அழிக்கவும் ஒன்றிணைக்கவும் முடியும். Contacts உங்கள் ஆதாரங்கள் அனைத்திலிருந்தும் தொடர்புகளைச் சேகரித்து ஒரே இடத்தில் உங்கள் தொடர்புகளை நிர்வகிக்கும் வசதியை அளிக்கிறது.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sv">Kontakter lagrar och organiserar dina kontakters information. Du kan skapa, redigera, ta bort och länka ihop delar av information om dina kontakter. Kontakter sammanför detaljerna från alla dina källor och tillhandahåller en central plats för att hantera dina kontakter.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sr@latin">Kontakti čuva i sređuje podatke vaših kontakata. Možete da stvarate, uređujete, brišete i svezujete zajedno delove podataka o vašim kontaktima. Kontakti objedinjuje pojedinosti sa svih vaših izvora obezbeđujući središnje mesto za upravljanje vašim kontaktima.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sr">Контакти чува и сређује податке ваших контаката. Можете да стварате, уређујете, бришете и свезујете заједно делове података о вашим контактима. Контакти обједињује појединости са свих ваших извора обезбеђујући средишње место за управљање вашим контактима.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sl">Program omogoča urejanje in shranjevanje podatkov o stikih. Mogoče je urejati, ustvarjati, brisati in povezovati različne podatke. Program združuje podatke iz različnih virov in ponuja osrednje mesto za prikaz stikov.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sk">Aplikácia kontakty udržiava a organizuje informácie o vašich kontaktoch. Môžete vytvárať, upravovať, mazať a spájať informácie o vašich kontaktoch. Aplikácia kontakty zhromažďuje podrobnosti zo všetkých vašich zdrojov a umožňuje centralizovanú správu kontaktov.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ru">Приложение «Контакты» помогает управлять информацией о контактах. Вы можете создавать, изменять, удалять и связывать вместе сведения о ваших контактах. Приложение объединяет информацию со всех ваших источников, предоставляя централизованный способ управления контактами.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ro">Contacte păstrează și organizează informațiile de contact. Puteți crea, edita, șterge și conecta împreună fragmente de informații despre contacte. Contacte agregă detaliile de la toate sursele furnizând o locație centralizată pentru gestionarea contactelor.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt_BR">O aplicativo Contatos mantém e organiza as informações dos seus contatos. Você pode criar, editar, excluir ou vincular porções de informação sobre seus contatos. O aplicativo Contatos agrega os detalhes de todas as suas fontes, fornecendo um local centralizado para o gerenciamento de seus contatos.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">O Contactos mantém e organiza a informação dos seus contactos. Pode criar, editar, apagar e juntar diferentes pedaços de informação sobre os seus contactos. O Contactos agrega os detalhes de todas as suas fontes fornecendo-lhe um local centralizado para gerir os seus contactos.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pl">Menedżer kontaktów GNOME umożliwia przechowywanie i uporządkowanie informacji o kontaktach. Można je tworzyć, modyfikować, usuwać i łączyć. Program zbiera dane ze wszystkich podanych źródeł, co czyni go istnym centrum zarządzania kontaktami.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pa">ਸੰਪਰਕ ਤੁਹਾਡੇ ਸੰਪਰਕਾਂ ਦੀ ਜਾਣਕਾਰੀ ਨੂੰ ਸੰਭਾਲਦੀ ਅਤੇ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦਾ ਪ੍ਰਬੰਧ ਕਰਦੀ ਹੈ। ਤੁਸੀਂ ਆਪਣੇ ਸੰਪਰਕਾਂ ਬਾਰੇ ਜਾਣਕਾਰੀ ਦੇ ਭਾਗਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਬਣਾਉਣ, ਸੋਧਣ, ਹਟਾਉਣ ਅਤੇ ਆਪਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਜੋੜ ਸਕਦੇ ਹੋ। ਸੰਪਰਕ ਤੁਹਾਡੇ ਸੰਪਰਕਾਂ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਬੰਧ ਲਈ ਇੱਕ ਸਾਂਝੀ ਥਾਂ ਉਪਲੱਬਧ ਕਰਵਾਉਣ ਤੁਹਾਡੇ ਸਭ ਸਰੋਤਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਵੇਰਵੇ ਨੂੰ ਇੱਕਠਾ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ।</p>
    <p xml:lang="or">ସମ୍ପର୍କଗୁଡ଼ିକ ଆପଣଙ୍କର ସମ୍ପର୍କ ସୂଚନାକୁ ରଖିଥାଏ ଏବଂ ସଠିକ ବ୍ୟବସ୍ଥା କରିଥାଏ। ଆପଣ ସମ୍ପର୍କଗୁଡ଼ିକ ବିଷୟରେ ସୂଚନା ସୃଷ୍ଟି, ସମ୍ପାଦନ, ଅପସାରଣ କରିପାରିବେ ଏବଂ ଯୋଡ଼ିପାରିବେ। ସମ୍ପର୍କ ଆପଣଙ୍କର ବିଭିନ୍ନ ଉତ୍ସରୁ ସୂଚନା ଏକତ୍ରିତ କରି ଏକ ସ୍ଥାନରେ ପରିଚାଳନା କରିଥାଏ।</p>
    <p xml:lang="oc">Contacts consèrva e organiza las informacions ligadas a vòstres contactes. Podètz crear, editar, suprimir e religar d'informacions a prepaus de vòstres contactes. Contacts regropa los detalhs que provenon de totas vòstras fonts, e vos provesís atal un endreit centralizat per gerir vòstres contactes.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">Contacten slaat de informatie over uw contacten op en organiseert die. U kunt informatie over uw contacten aanmaken, bewerken, wissen en samenvoegen. Contacten verzamelt de details uit al uw informatiebronnen waarmee het een centrale plaats biedt van waaruit u uw contacten kunt beheren.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ne">सम्पर्कहरू तपाईंको सम्पर्क जानकारी राख्छ र व्यवस्थित गर्दछ। तपाईं सिर्जना गर्न, सम्पादन गर्न, मेटाउन र तपाईंको सम्पर्कहरूको बारेमा टुक्रा जानकारी को साथ लिङ्क गर्न सक्नुहुनेछ। सम्पर्कहरू तपाइँका सम्पर्कहरु को ब्यवस्थापन को लागी एक केंद्रीकृत स्थान प्रदान गर्ने सबै विवरणहरु को विवरण को एकत्र गर्दछ।</p>
    <p xml:lang="nb">Kontakter tar vare på og organiserer kontaktinformasjon. Du kan lage, redigere, slette og lenke sammen informasjonselementer om dine kontakter. Kontakter sammenstiller detaljene fra alle kilder og gir deg et sentralisert sted å håndtere dine kontakter.</p>
    <p xml:lang="mr">काँटॅक्ट्स तुमची संपर्क माहिती जतन करते आणि आयोजीत करते. तुम्ही संपर्कांविषयी माहितीचे निर्माण, संपादन, नष्ट करणे आणि एकत्रीकरण करू शकता. काँटॅक्ट्स सर्व स्रोतपासून तपशीलावर गोळा करते आणि संपर्कांना व्यवस्थापीत करण्यासाठी एक केंद्रीय ठिकाण पुरवते.</p>
    <p xml:lang="lv">“Kontakti” jums ļauj organizēt informāciju par saviem kontaktiem. Jūs varat izveidot, rediģēt, dzēst un saistīt kopā informāciju par saviem kontaktiem. “Kontakti” apvienot informāciju no visiem jūsu avotiem un sniedz centralizētu vietu kontaktu pārvaldībai.</p>
    <p xml:lang="lt">Kontaktai saugo ir tvarko kontaktų informaciją. Galite sukurti, keisti, trinti ir susieti kartu informaciją apie savo kontaktus. Kontaktai surenka informaciją iš visų šaltinių ir pateikia centralizuotą vietą jų tvarkymui.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ko">연락처에서는 연락처 정보를 유지하고 정리합니다. 연락처의 여러가지 정보를 만들고, 편집하고, 지우며, 각각의 정보를 연결할 수 있습니다. 연락처는 연락처를 관리하는 집중형 수단을 제공하여 원본에서 세부 정보를 수집합니다.</p>
    <p xml:lang="kn">ಕಾಂಟ್ಯಾಕ್ಟ್ಸ್‌ ನಿಮ್ಮ ಸಂಪರ್ಕವಿಳಾಸಗಳ ಮಾಹಿತಿಯನ್ನು ಇರಿಸಿಕೊಳ್ಳಲು ಮತ್ತು ವ್ಯವಸ್ಥಿತವಾಗಿ ಜೋಡಿಸಲು ನಿಮಗೆ ನೆರವಾಗುತ್ತದೆ. ನೀವು ನಿಮ್ಮಲ್ಲಿನ ಸಂಪರ್ಕವಿಳಾಸಗಳ ಕುರಿತಾದ ಮಾಹಿತಿಗಳನ್ನು ರಚಿಸಲು, ಸಂಪಾದಿಸಲು, ಅಳಿಸಲು ಮತ್ತು ಒಟ್ಟಿಗೆ ಜೋಡಿಸಲು ಸಾಧ್ಯವಿರುತ್ತದೆ. ಕಾಂಟ್ಯಾಕ್ಟ್ಸ್‌ ನಿಮ್ಮ ಸಂಪರ್ಕವಿಳಾಸಗಳನ್ನು ನಿರ್ವಹಿಸಲು ಒಂದು ಕೇಂದ್ರೀಕೃತವಾದ ಸ್ಥಳವನ್ನು ಒದಗಿಸುವ ಮೂಲಕ ನಿಮ್ಮ ಎಲ್ಲಾ ಆಕರಗಳಿಂದ ವಿವರಗಳನ್ನು ಕ್ರೋಢೀಕರಿಸುತ್ತದೆ.</p>
    <p xml:lang="kk">Контакттар қолданбасы сіздің контакттар ақпаратын сақтайды және реттейді. Сіз контакттарыңыз жөнінде ақпаратты жасап, түзетіп, өшіріп және өзара сілтей аласыз. Контакттар қолданбасы барлық көздерден ақпаратты біріктіріп ұстайды және контакттарды басқару үшін орталықтанған орны болып табылады.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ja">連絡先情報を維持、管理できる連絡先アプリです。連絡先の作成、編集、削除はもちろん、複数の連絡先を統合することもできます。また他のソースの連絡先情報をまとめることができ、このアプリから一括して連絡先管理を行うことができます。</p>
    <p xml:lang="it">«Contatti» mantiene e organizza le informazioni sui propri contatti. È possibile creare, modificare, eliminare e collegare parti di informazioni unendo i dettagli di tutte le sorgenti in un unico posto centralizzato per la loro gestione.</p>
    <p xml:lang="is">Tengiliðaskráin heldur utan um upplýsingar varðandi tengiliði. Þú getur búið til tangiliði, breytt þeim og eytt, og tengt ýmsar upplýsingar við tengiliðina þína. GNOME Contacts safnar saman atriðum frá ýmsum uppsprettum í einn stað þar sem þú getur sýslað með tengiliðina þína.</p>
    <p xml:lang="id">Kontak menyimpan dan mengorganisasi informasi kontak Anda. Anda dapat membuat, menyunting, menghapus, dan menaut bersama penggalan-penggalan informasi tentang kontak Anda. Kontak mengagregasi rincian dari semua sumber Anda dan menyediakan suatu tempat terpusat untuk mengelola kontak Anda.</p>
    <p xml:lang="hu">A Névjegyek tárolja és rendezi a névjegyek információit. Létrehozhat, szerkeszthet, törölhet névjegyeket és információkat köthet össze velük kapcsolatban. A Névjegyek összegyűjti minden forrás részleteit egy központi helyet biztosítva azok kezeléséhez.</p>
    <p xml:lang="hr">Kontakti čuvaju i drže organiziranim vaše informacije kontakata. Možete stvarati, uređivati, brisati i spojiti dijelove informacija vaših kontakata. Kontakti stvaraju pojedinosti iz svih vaših izvora omogućujući središnje mjesto za upravljanje vašim kontaktima.</p>
    <p xml:lang="hi">संपर्क आपके संपर्क सूचना को बनाए रखता है और संगठित रखता है. आप अपने संपर्क के बारे में जानकारी और लिंक को इकट्ठा कर सकते हैं. संपर्क आपके संपर्क प्रबंधित करने के लिए एक केंद्रीकृत स्थान प्रदान करता है.</p>
    <p xml:lang="he">אנשי קשר שומר ומארגן את מידע אנשי הקשר שלך. ניתן ליצור, לערוך, למחוק ולקשר יחד חתיכות של מידע על אודות אנשי הקשר שלך. אנשי קשר אוגר את הפרטים מכל המקורות שלך לספק מקום מרכזי לניהול אנשי הקשר שלך.</p>
    <p xml:lang="gu">સંપર્કો તમારી સંપર્ક જાણકારીને સંચાલિત રાખે છે. તમે બનાવી, ફેરફાર અને કાઢી શકો છો અને તમારા સંપર્કો વિશે જાણકારીઓને ભેગી કરી કડી કરી શકો છો. સંપર્કો તમારાં સંપર્કોને સંચાલિત કરવા માટે કેન્દ્રિત જગ્યાને પૂરી પાડી તમારા બધા સ્ત્રોતોમાંથી વિગતોને એકત્રિત કરે છે.</p>
    <p xml:lang="gl">Contactos mantén e organiza a información dos seus contactos. Pode crear, editar, eliminar e ligar partes de información sobre os seus contactos. Os contactos agregan a información de todas as súas orixes fornecendo un lugar centralizado para xestionar os seus contactos.</p>
    <p xml:lang="gd">Cumaidh Luchd-aithne fiosrachadh mun luchd-aithne agad an rian. ’S urrainn dhut bloighean fiosrachaidh mun luchd-aithne agad a chruthachadh, a dheasachadh, a sguabadh às agus a cheangal ri chèile. Cuiridh Luchd-aithne a h-uile fiosrachadh o na tùsan agad ri chèile gus prìomh ionad a chruthachadh gus an luchd-aithne agad a stiùireadh.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fur">Contats al manten e al ministre lis informazions dai tiei contats. Tu puedis creâ, modificâ, scancelâ e leâ adun tocs di informazions dai tiei contats. Contats al unìs i detais di dutis lis tôs sorzints dant un sisteme centralizât par ministrâ i tiei contats.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fr">Contacts conserve et organise les informations liées à vos contacts. Vous pouvez créer, éditer, supprimer et relier des informations à propos de vos contacts. Contacts regroupe les détails provenant de toutes vos sources, vous fournissant ainsi un endroit centralisé pour gérer vos contacts.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fi">Yhteystietosovellus säilyttää ja hallinnoi yhteystietojasi. Voit luoda, muokata, poistaa ja linkittää yhteystietoja. Yhteystietosovellus kerää yhteen lukuisista eri lähteistä kaikki yhteystietoihisi liittyvät yksityiskohdat.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fa">آشنایان، اطّلاعات آشنایانتان را نگه‌داری و منظّم می‌کند. می‌توانید قطعه‌های اطّلاعات دربارهٔ آشنایانتان را ایجاد، ویرایش و حذف کرده یا به هم پیوند بزنید. آشنایان جزئیات را از همهٔ منابعتان جمع می‌کند تا مکانی مرکزی برای مدیریت آشنایانیتان به‌وجود آورد.</p>
    <p xml:lang="eu">Kontaktuak zure kontaktuen informazioa antolatu eta gordetzen du. Zure kontaktuei buruzko informazio zatiak sortu, editatu, ezabatu eta elkarrekin esteka dezakezu. 'Kontaktuak' aplikazioak zure iturburuetako xehetasunak gehitzen ditu zure kontaktuen kudeaketa leku zentralizatu batean edukitzeko.</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">Contactos mantiene y organiza la información de sus contactos. Puede crear, editar, eliminar y enlazar fragmentos de información sobre sus contactos. Contactos añade los detalles de todas sus fuentes, proporcionando un lugar centralizado para gestionar sus contactos.</p>
    <p xml:lang="eo">Kontaktaro konservas kaj organizas viajn kontakt-informojn. Vi povas krei, redakti, forigi kaj bindi erojn de informoj pri viaj kontaktoj. Kontaktaro kombinas la detalojn de ĉiuj de viaj fontoj provizante centritan lokon por mastrumi viajn kontaktojn.</p>
    <p xml:lang="en_GB">Contacts keeps and organise your contacts information. You can create, edit, delete and link together pieces of information about your contacts. Contacts aggregates the details from all your sources providing a centralised place for managing your contacts.</p>
    <p xml:lang="el">Οι επαφές σας βοηθούν να διατηρείτε και να οργανώνετε τις πληροφορίες των επαφών σας. Μπορείτε να δημιουργήσετε, επεξεργαστείτε, διαγράψετε και να συνδέσετε κομμάτια πληροφορίας των επαφών σας. Η εφαρμογή επαφές ενοποιεί τις λεπτομέρειες από όλες τις πηγές και σας παρέχει ένα κεντρικό σημείο διαχείρισης των επαφών σας.</p>
    <p xml:lang="de">Die Kontaktverwaltung speichert und organisiert Informationen Ihrer Kontakte. Sie können Kontaktinformationen erstellen, bearbeiten, löschen und miteinander verknüpfen. Die Kontaktverwaltung fasst die Details aus Ihren Quellen zusammen und bietet einen zentralen Ort, um Ihre Kontakte zu verwalten.</p>
    <p xml:lang="da">Programmet Kontakter opbevarer og organiserer kontaktperson-information. Du kan oprette, redigere og sammenkæde stykker af information om dine kontaktpersoner. Kontakter samler detaljerne fra alle dine kilder og giver derved et centraliseret sted for håndtering af dine kontaktpersoner.</p>
    <p xml:lang="cs">Kontakty uchovávají a třídí vaše kontakty. Různé kousky svých kontaktních informací můžete vytvářet, upravovat, mazat a spojovat dohromady. Aplikace Kontakty seskupuje údaje ze všech vašich zdrojů a poskytuje vám místo, kde je můžete spravovat jednotně.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca@valencia">El Contactes manté i organitza la informació dels vostres contactes. Podeu crear, editar, suprimir i enllaçar informació sobre els vostres contactes. El Contactes afig els detalls des de tots els orígens de manera que des d'un lloc centralitzat es poden gestionar els vostres contactes.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca">El Contactes manté i organitza la informació dels vostres contactes. Podeu crear, editar, suprimir i enllaçar informació sobre els vostres contactes. El Contactes afegeix els detalls des de tots els orígens de manera que des d'un lloc centralitzat es poden gestionar els vostres contactes.</p>
    <p xml:lang="bs">Kontakti čuva i organizira podatke Vaših kontakata . Možete stvoriti , uređivati ​​, brisati i povezivati ​​dijelove informacija o svojim kontaktima . Kontakti prikuplja podatke iz svih vaših izvora pružajući centralizirano mjesto za upravljanje kontaktima.</p>
    <p xml:lang="bn_IN">পরিচিতিগুলি অাপনার পরিচিতি তথ্য রাখে এবং ব্যবস্থাপিত করে। অাপনি অাপনার পরিচিতিগুলির বিষয়ে তথ্য তৈরি করতে, সম্পাদনা করতে, মুছতে এবং লিঙ্ক করতে পারবেন। পরিচিতি অাপনার সমস্ত সোর্স থেকে বিস্তারিত একত্রিত করে অাপনার পরিচিতিগুলি ব্যবস্থাপনার এক কেন্দ্রীয় স্থান প্রদান করে।</p>
    <p xml:lang="be">Кіраўнік кантактаў захоўвае і парадкуе вашы кантакты. З яго дапамогай можна ствараць, рэдагаваць, выдаляць і аб'ядноўваць звесткі аб вашых кантактах. Кіраўнік збірае звесткі з усіх магчымых крыніц і прадастаўляе цэнтралізаваны спосаб кіравання кантактамі.</p>
    <p xml:lang="as">পৰিচয়সমূহে আপোনাৰ পৰিচয়সমূহৰ তথ্যক সংৰক্ষিত আৰু সংঘঠিত ৰাখে। আপুনি আপোনাৰ পৰিচয়সমূহৰ বিষয়ে তথ্য সৃষ্টি, সম্পাদন, মচা আৰু সংযোগ কৰিব পাৰিব। পৰিচয়সমূহে আপোনাৰ সকলো উৎসৰ পৰা বিৱৰণ একত্ৰিত কৰে যাৰ সহায়ত আপোনাৰ পৰিচয়সমূহ ব্যৱস্থাপনা কৰিবলৈ এটা কেনদ্ৰিত স্থান পায়।</p>
    <p>
      Contacts will also integrate with online address books and automatically
      link contacts from different online sources.
    </p>
    <p xml:lang="zh_TW">《聯絡人》也會與線上通訊錄整合，並且自動連結來自不同線上來源的聯絡人。</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh_HK">Contacts 也會與網上通訊錄整合，並且自動連結來自不同網上來源的聯絡人。</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh_CN">联系人也可以整合在线地址簿，并自动链接到各种在线帐号的联系人。</p>
    <p xml:lang="vi">Sổ danh bạ cũng được kết hợp với các sổ địa chỉ trên mạng khác và tự động liên kết các liên lạc từ các nguồn khác nhau trên mạng.</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">Контакти також інтегровані з мережевими адресними книгами і автоматично сполучать контакти з різних джерел.</p>
    <p xml:lang="tr">Kişiler ayrıca çevrim içi adres defterleriyle de birleşerek çeşitli çevrim içi kaynaklardaki kişileri kendiliğinden birbirine bağlar.</p>
    <p xml:lang="th">นอกจากนี้ สมุดผู้ติดต่อยังเชื่อมรวมกับสมุดที่อยู่ออนไลน์ และเชื่อมโยงผู้ติดต่อจากแหล่งออนไลน์ต่างๆ โดยอัตโนมัติ</p>
    <p xml:lang="tg">Барномаи "Тамосҳо" инчунин бо китобҳои суроғаҳои онлан якҷоя кор мекунад ва тамосҳоро аз манбаҳои онлайни гуногун ба таври худкор пайваст мекунад.</p>
    <p xml:lang="te">పరిచయాలు ఆన్‌లైన్ చిరునామా పుస్తకాలతో కలిసి మరియు స్వయంచాలకంగా విభిన్న ఆన్‌లైన్ మూలాలనుండి పరిచయాలను లింక్ చేయగలదు.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ta">Contacts ஆன்லைன் முகவரிப் புத்தகங்களுடனும் ஒருங்கிணைந்து உங்கள் வெவ்வேறு ஆன்லைன் ஆதாரங்களில் இருந்தும் தொடர்புகளை தானாக இணைத்து வழங்கும்.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sv">Kontakter integrerar med adressböcker på nätet och länkar automatiskt kontakter från olika källor.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sr@latin">Kontakti će se takođe sjediniti sa imenicima na mreži i samostalno će povezati kontakte sa različitih izvora na mreži.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sr">Контакти ће се такође сјединити са именицима на мрежи и самостално ће повезати контакте са различитих извора на мрежи.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sl">Stiki bodo povezani tudi z omrežnimi imeniki in bodo samodejno povezani med različnimi viri.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sk">Aplikácia kontakty sa dokáže spojiť s mnohými adresárovými službami a dokáže prepájať kontakty z viacerých zdrojov.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ru">Приложение «Контакты» также  выполнит интеграцию с сетевой адресной книгой и автоматически свяжет контакты из различных сетевых источников.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ro">Contacte va integra și agendele de contacte online și va conecta automat contacte de la surse online diferite.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt_BR">O aplicativo Contatos também se integra aos catálogos de endereços on-line e automaticamente vincula contatos de diferentes fontes on-line.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">O Contactos irá também integrar-se com os seus livros de endereços online e juntar automaticamente os contactos de diferentes fontes.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pl">Menedżer kontaktów GNOME można również zintegrować z internetowymi książkami adresowymi i automatycznie łączyć kontakty z różnych źródeł.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pa">ਸੰਪਰਕ ਆਨਲਾਈਨ ਸਿਰਨਾਵਾਂ ਕਿਤਾਬਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਜੁੜ ਸਕਦੀ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਸੰਪਰਕਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਵੱਖ-ਵੱਖ ਆਨਲਾਈਨ ਸਰੋਤਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਆਪਣੇ-ਆਪ ਲਿੰਕ ਕਰ ਸਕੇਗਾ।</p>
    <p xml:lang="or">ସମ୍ପର୍କଗୁଡ଼ିକ ଅନଲାଇନ ଠିକଣା ପୁସ୍ତକ ସହିତ ମଧ୍ଯ ସଯୁକ୍ତ ହୋଇଥାଏ ଏବଂ ସ୍ୱୟଂଚାଳିତ ଭାବରେ ସମ୍ପର୍କଗୁଡ଼ିକୁ ବିଭିନ୍ନ ଅନଲାଇନ ଉତ୍ସରୁ ସଂଯୁକ୍ତ କରିଥାଏ।</p>
    <p xml:lang="oc">Contacts permet tanben l'integracion de quasernets d'adreças en linha e religa automaticament los contactes de diferentas fonts en linha.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">Contacten integreert ook met online adresboeken en koppelt automatisch contacten uit verschillende online bronnen.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ne">सम्पर्कहरू अनलाइन ठेगाना पुस्तकहरूसँग पनि एकीकृत हुनेछन् र सम्पर्कहरू स्वचालित रूपमा अनलाइन अनलाइन स्रोतहरूबाट लिङ्क गर्नुहोस्।</p>
    <p xml:lang="nb">Kontakter kan også integreres med adressebøker på nett, og lenker automatisk sammen kontakter fra forskjellige kilder på nettet.</p>
    <p xml:lang="mr">संपर्कांना ऑनलाइन पत्ता पुस्तकांशी एकत्रीत करणे आणि विविध ऑनलाइन स्रोतपासून संपर्कांना स्व जुळणे शक्य आहे.</p>
    <p xml:lang="lv">Kontakti arī ir integrēti ar tiešsaistes adrešu grāmatām un automātiski saista kontaktus ar dažādiem tiešsaistes avotiem.</p>
    <p xml:lang="lt">Kontaktai taip pat gali integruotis su internetinėmis adresų knygomis bei automatiškai susieti kontaktus iš skirtingų internetinių šaltinių.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ko">연락처는 온라인 주소록을 통합하며 여러 온라인 원본 연락처를 자동으로 이어줍니다.</p>
    <p xml:lang="kn">ಕಾಂಟ್ಯಾಕ್ಟ್ಸ್ ನಿಮ್ಮ ಆನ್‌ಲೈನ್ ವಿಳಾಸ ಪುಸ್ತಕಗಳನ್ನು ಸಂಯೋಜಿತಗೊಳಿಸುತ್ತದೆ ಮತ್ತು ಸ್ವಯಂಚಾಲಿತವಾಗಿ ವಿವಿಧ ಆನ್‌ಲೈನ್ ಆಕರಗಳಿಂದ ಸಂಪರ್ಕವಿಳಾಸಗಳನ್ನು ಸಂಪರ್ಕಜೋಡಿಸುತ್ತದೆ.</p>
    <p xml:lang="kk">Сонымен қатар, контакттар сіздің желідегі адрестік кітаптарды қолданады және бірнеше желідегі көзден контакттарды автоматты түрде қолжетерлік қылады.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ja">オンラインのアドレス帳と連動させることで、複数のオンラインソースに存在する連絡先も自動的にリンクできます。</p>
    <p xml:lang="it">Inoltre verranno integrate le rubriche online e verranno automaticamente uniti i contatti da diverse sorgenti online.</p>
    <p xml:lang="is">GNOME Tengiliðir samtvinnur einnig upplýsingar úr nafnaskrám á netinu og tengir færslur sjálfkrafa við ýmis netforrit og tilföng af internetinu.</p>
    <p xml:lang="id">Kontak juga akan mengintegrasi dengan buku alamat daring dan secara otomatis menaut kontak-kontak dari sumber-sumber daring yang berbeda.</p>
    <p xml:lang="hu">A Névjegyek egyesülni fog az online címjegyzékekkel és automatikusan összekapcsolja a különböző online forrásokból származó névjegyeket.</p>
    <p xml:lang="hr">Kontakti će se isto integrirati s mrežnim adresarom i automatski povezati kontakte sa različitih mrežnih izvora.</p>
    <p xml:lang="hi">संपर्क ऑनलाइन पता पुस्तिका से एकीकृत होगा और भिन्न ऑनलाइन स्रोत से स्वतः संपर्क को लिंक करेगा.</p>
    <p xml:lang="he">אנשי קשר גם משולב עם פנקסי כתובות מקוונים ומקשר אנשי קשר באופן אוטומטי ממקורות מקוונים שונים.</p>
    <p xml:lang="gu">સંપર્કો ઓનલાઇન સરનામાં પુસ્તિકાઓ સાથે પણ એકત્રિત થયેલ હશે અને આપમેળે વિવિધ ઓનલાઇન સ્ત્રોતોમાંથી સંપર્કોની કડી કરે છે.</p>
    <p xml:lang="gl">Contactos tamén se integra con cadernos de enderezos en liña e liga automaticamente contactos de diferentes orixes en liña.</p>
    <p xml:lang="gd">Amalaichidh Luchd-aithne le leabhraichean nan seòladh air loidhne cuideachd ’s nì e ceangal ri luchd-aithne o chaochladh de thùsan air loidhne gu fèin-obrachail.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fur">In plui a vegnaran integradis lis rubrichis in-linie e a vegnaran unîts in maniere automatiche i contats di diviersis sorzints in-linie.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fr">Contacts permet également l’intégration de carnets d’adresses en ligne et relie automatiquement les contacts de différentes sources en ligne.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fi">Yhteystietosovellus tuo yhteen verkossa olevat eri osoitekirjat ja linkittää automaattisesti yhteystiedot eri verkkolähteistä.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fa">آشنایان هم‌چنین با دفترچه‌های نشانی برخط یک‌پارچه شده و به صورت خودکار آشنایانیی از منابع برخط مختلف را به هم پیوند می‌دهد.</p>
    <p xml:lang="eu">Kontaktuak lineako helbide-liburuekin batera daiteke, eta lineako iturburu desberdinetako kontaktuak automatikoki esteka ditzake.</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">Contactos también se integra con las libretas de direcciones en línea y enlaza contactos automáticamente de diferentes fuentes en línea.</p>
    <p xml:lang="eo">Kontaktaro integras kun retaj adresaroj kaj aŭtomate bindas kontaktojn de diversaj retaj fontoj.</p>
    <p xml:lang="en_GB">Contacts will also integrate with online address books and automatically link contacts from different online sources.</p>
    <p xml:lang="el">Η εφαρμογή επαφές ενσωματώνεται με διαδικτυακά βιβλία διευθύνσεων και αυτόματα συνδέονται οι επαφές από διαφορετικές διαδικτυακές πηγές.</p>
    <p xml:lang="de">Die Kontaktverwaltung integriert sich auch in Ihre Online-Adressbücher und verknüpft Kontakte aus verschiedenen Online-Quellen.</p>
    <p xml:lang="da">Kontakter kan også integrere sig med adressebøger på nettet og automatisk sammenkæde kontaktpersoner fra forskellige kilder på nettet.</p>
    <p xml:lang="cs">Kontakty rovněž integrují on-line adresáře a automaticky propojují kontakty z různých on-line zdrojů.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca@valencia">El Contactes també s'integra amb llibretes d'adreces en línia i enllaçarà automàticament els contactes des de diferents orígens en línia.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca">El Contactes també s'integra amb llibretes d'adreces en línia i enllaçarà automàticament els contactes des de diferents orígens en línia.</p>
    <p xml:lang="bs">Kontakti će se također integrirati sa online adresarom i automatski povezati kontakte iz različitih online izvora .</p>
    <p xml:lang="bn_IN">পরিচিতিগুলি অনলাইন ঠিকানা বইগুলির সংগেও একত্রিত হবে এবং স্বয়ংক্রিয় ভাবে অালাদা অনলাইন সোর্সগুলি থেকে পরিচিতিগুলি লিঙ্ক করবে।</p>
    <p xml:lang="be">Кіраўнік кантактаў таксама інтэграваны з сеціўнымі адраснымі кнігамі і аўтаматычна аб'ядноўвае кантакты з розных сеціўных крыніц.</p>
    <p xml:lang="as">পৰিচয়সমূহে লগতে অনলাইন ঠিকনা বহীসমূহৰ সৈতে অনুকূলন কৰিব আৰু বিভিন্ন অনলাইন উৎসসমূহৰ পৰা পৰিচয়সমূহ সংযোগ কৰিব।</p>
  </description>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot height="575" width="800" type="default">
      <image>
      https://wiki.gnome.org/Apps/Contacts?action=AttachFile&amp;do=get&amp;target=appdata.png
    </image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <releases>
    <release date="2020-01-05" version="3.35.1">
      <description>
        <p>
          This is the first unstable release in the 3.35 development series,
          with the following improvements:
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>
            You can now use a "back" gesture on touch devices to go back to the
            contact list when viewing or editing a contact
          </li>
          <li>Contacts now works on even smaller screens</li>
          <li>Nightly now show off with a fancy new icon</li>
          <li>
            Bugfix: if another app opens Contacts, this still works even if
            it's not running
          </li>
        </ul>
        <p>This release also updates translations in several languages.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2019-09-09" version="3.34">
      <description>
        <p>
          Version 3.34 is a stable release, with the following major
          improvements since 3.32:
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>Updated avatars which follow the GNOME avatar style</li>
          <li>Better accessibility with mnemonics for the setup window</li>
          <li>A new --search option for the command-line</li>
          <li>Fixed issues when using the webcam to add an avatar</li>
          <li>Fixed searching contacts in GNOME Shell returning no results</li>
        </ul>
        <p>This release also updates translations in several languages.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2019-09-04" version="3.33.92">
      <description>
        <p>
          This is the last unstable release in the 3.33 development series,
          with the following improvements since 3.33.91:
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>Updated the man page</li>
        </ul>
        <p>This release also updates translations in several languages.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2019-08-20" version="3.33.91">
      <description>
        <p>
          This is the next unstable release in the 3.33 development series,
          some would say a beta, with the following improvements:
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>
            Make the avatars more in line with the other apps in the GNOME
            ecoosystem. If possible, the initials will be used to make an
            avatar if none is available.
          </li>
          <li>Fix searching contacts from GNOME Shell returning no results</li>
          <li>Add a small description of the --search option</li>
        </ul>
        <p>This release also updates translations in several languages.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2019-07-22" version="3.33.4">
      <description>
        <p>
          This is the second unstable release in the 3.33 development series,
          with the following improvements:
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>Flatpak: Allow webcam access (and other small fixes)</li>
          <li>Even better integration with CI</li>
          <li>Add mnemonics to the setup window</li>
        </ul>
        <p>This release also updates translations in several languages.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2019-04-24" version="3.33.1">
      <description>
        <p>
          This is the first unstable release in the 3.33 development series,
          with the following improvements:
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>
            Added a show-contact application action, so other applications
            can activate Contacts to show a specific contact
          </li>
          <li>Reverted an accidental change in the Appstream ID</li>
          <li>Pass along the right printf-format to MessageDialogs</li>
        </ul>
        <p>This release also updates translations in several languages.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2019-03-12" version="3.32">
      <description>
        <p>
          Version 3.32 is the next stable release, with the following major
          improvements since 3.30:
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>A new, modern icon</li>
          <li>A responsive UI: Contacts now works on all screen sizes!</li>
          <li>
            Property types are now handled more consistently, fixing some minor
            issues, e.g. types mixing translations with the ones from Google.
          </li>
          <li>A few minor performance optimizations</li>
          <li>Solved a bug where the birthday did not change</li>
          <li>Fixed a crash when right-clicking in the contact list</li>
        </ul>
        <p>This release also updates translations in several languages.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2019-02-06" version="3.31.90">
      <description>
        <p>
          This is the next unstable release in the 3.31 development series,
          with the following improvements:
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>
            The interface now adapts to the size of its window, making it
            possible to use on smaller screens (such as phones)
          </li>
        </ul>
        <p>This release also updates translations in several languages.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2019-01-09" version="3.31.4">
      <description>
        <p>
          This is the next unstable release in the 3.31 development series,
          with the following improvements:
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>
            Small improvements for the "types" of properties ("Home", "Work",
            …). Contacts should now also be able to more easily identify
            untranslated properties from Google Contacts.
          </li>
          <li>Some UI tweaks for the primary menu</li>
          <li>The appdata file and the desktop file are now validated by CI</li>
        </ul>
        <p>This release also updates translations in several languages.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2018-12-10" version="3.31.3">
      <description>
        <p>
          This is the first unstable release in the 3.31 development series,
          with the following improvements:
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>An updated application icon</li>
          <li>Dropped the app menu</li>
          <li>Added a dependency on libhandy</li>
          <li>Fix birthday not being properly saved</li>
          <li>Telepathy is now disabled by default</li>
          <li>Flatpak fixes</li>
        </ul>
        <p>This release also updates translations in several languages.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2018-09-03" version="3.30">
      <description>
        <p>
          Version 3.30 is the next stable release, with the following major
          improvements since 3.28:
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>Tweaks to the avatar selector UI</li>
          <li>Several fixes for the Flatpak build</li>
          <li>OARS content ratings</li>
        </ul>
        <p>This release also updates translations in several languages.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2018-08-27" version="3.29.92">
      <description>
        <p>
          This is the last unstable release in the 3.29 development series,
          with the following improvements:
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>The avatar selector now uses the native file chooser</li>
          <li>Added OARS content rating</li>
          <li>Restructured the code to allow automated tests</li>
          <li>Several flatpak fixes</li>
        </ul>
        <p>This release also updates translations in several languages.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2018-05-24" version="3.29.2">
      <description>
        <p>
          This is the first unstable release in the 3.29 development series,
          with the following improvements:
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>The avatar selection UI has been revamped</li>
          <li>
            Use GNOME's Meson conventions: compilation options can now no
            longer have an auto value. Some have also been renamed to drop the
            "with-" prefix.
          </li>
          <li>The Flatpak manifest was improved in several ways.</li>
          <li>Extended the CI pipeline to use flatpak</li>
        </ul>
        <p>This release also updates translations in several languages.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2018-03-12" version="3.28">
      <description>
        <p>
          Version 3.28 is a stable release, with the following major improvements:
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>Favorite contacts, which are shown at the top of the contact list.</li>
          <li>Sort contacts by their first name or surname.</li>
          <li>Small tweaks to the UI, such as a more welcoming setup screen and rounded avatars.</li>
          <li>Performance improvements to the GNOME Shell search provider.</li>
          <li>A slightly decreased memory usage.</li>
        </ul>
        <p>This release also updates translations in several languages.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2018-03-05" version="3.27.92">
      <description>
        <p>
          This is the fourth unstable (beta) release in the 3.27 development series,
          with the following improvements:
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>The titlebar is now updated when a contact's name changes.</li>
          <li>The window will now remember its size and restore it on the next start.</li>
          <li>Postal addresses are now sorted before notes.</li>
        </ul>
        <p>This release also updates translations in several languages.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2018-02-05" version="3.27.90">
      <description>
        <p>
          This is the third unstable release in the 3.27 development series,
          with the following improvements:
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>Support for favorite contacts. These contacts will be shown at the top of the list.</li>
          <li>Contacts now allows sorting by both first name and surname.</li>
          <li>Avatars are now displayed as a circle and are better optimized for memory usage.</li>
          <li>Selection mode can now be started by right-clicking the contact list.</li>
        </ul>
        <p>This release also updates translations in several languages.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2018-01-09" version="3.27.4">
      <description>
        <p>
          This is the second unstable release in the 3.27 development series,
          with the following improvements:
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>Contacts now has a shortcuts window</li>
          <li>Small tweaks to the setup screen</li>
          <li>Support --version as command-line argument</li>
          <li>Telepathy is no longer a mandatory dependency</li>
          <li>Support for maps can be disabled at compile time</li>
          <li>Improved the Shell search provider</li>
        </ul>
        <p>This release also updates translations in several languages.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2017-11-13" version="3.27.2">
      <description>
        <p>
          This is the first unstable release in the 3.27 development series,
          with the following improvements:
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>Contact properties are now sorted by type</li>
          <li>Avatars are now displayed using rounded border</li>
        </ul>
        <p>This release also updates translations in several languages.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2017-09-11" version="3.26.0">
      <description>
        <p>
          Version 3.26 is a stable release, with the following improvements:
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>Support for Flatpak</li>
          <li>Support for faster builds using Meson</li>
          <li>Saving notes in a contact now works again</li>
          <li>Some contact properties are now selectable</li>
          <li>Use our own app icon, rather than a predefined one</li>
        </ul>
        <p>This release also updates translations in several languages.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2017-09-05" version="3.25.92.1">
      <description>
        <p>
          This is an unstable release in the 3.25 development series,
          which fixes build errors in version 3.25.92.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2017-09-04" version="3.25.92">
      <description>
        <p>
          This is an unstable release in the 3.25 development series,
          with the following improvements:
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>Added experimental support for Flatpak</li>
          <li>Contacts can now be built with Meson</li>
          <li>Contacts now provides its own proper app icon</li>
          <li>Some labels in the contact sheet are now selectable</li>
        </ul>
        <p>
          The following bugs are also fixed:
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>Can't save notes in a contact</li>
          <li>Bumped minimal version of telepathy-glib, GTK+ and GLib</li>
        </ul>
        <p>This release also updates translations in several languages.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2017-07-17" version="3.25.4">
      <description>
        <p>
          This is an unstable release in the 3.25 development series,
          with the following improvements:
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>Contacts now provides its own application icon</li>
          <li>Small UI improvements to the avatar chooser dialog</li>
        </ul>
        <p>
          The following bugs are also fixed:
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>Folks now requires version 11.4 or higher</li>
          <li>Migrated away from intltool and libgd</li>
          <li>Got rid of a bunch of warnings and critical messsages</li>
          <li>Use the locale to translate months</li>
          <li>Added git.mk to automagically create .gitignores</li>
        </ul>
        <p>This release also updates translations in several languages.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
  <kudos>
    <kudo>AppMenu</kudo>
    <kudo>HiDpiIcon</kudo>
    <kudo>ModernToolkit</kudo>
    <kudo>SearchProvider</kudo>
  </kudos>
  <provides>
    <binary>gnome-contacts</binary>
  </provides>
  <url type="homepage">https://wiki.gnome.org/Apps/Contacts</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://gitlab.gnome.org/GNOME/gnome-contacts/issues</url>
  <url type="donation">http://www.gnome.org/friends/</url>
  <update_contact>nielsdg@gnome.org</update_contact>
  <project_group>GNOME</project_group>
  <developer_name>The GNOME Project</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="zh_TW">GNOME 專案</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="zh_CN">GNOME 项目</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="uk">Проєкт GNOME</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="tr">GNOME Projesi</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="sv">GNOME-projektet</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="sr">Гном пројекат</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="sl">Projekt GNOME</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="sk">Projekt GNOME</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="ru">Проект GNOME</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="ro">Proiectul GNOME</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="pt_BR">O Projeto GNOME</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="pl">Projekt GNOME</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="nl">Het Gnome-project</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="mjw">GNOME Project</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="lv">GNOME projekts</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="lt">GNOME projektas</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="ko">그놈 프로젝트</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="kk">GNOME жобасы</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="ja">The GNOME Project</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="it">Il progetto GNOME</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="is">GNOME verkefnið</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="id">Proyek GNOME</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="hu">A GNOME projekt</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="hr">GNOME projekt</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="gl">O Proxecto GNOME</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="fur">Il progjet GNOME</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="fr">Le projet GNOME</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="fi">Gnome-projekti</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="fa">پروژهٔ گنوم</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="eu">GNOME proiektua</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="es">El Proyecto GNOME</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="eo">La Projekto GNOME</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="en_GB">The GNOME Project</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="el">Το έργο GNOME</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="de">Das GNOME-Projekt</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="da">GNOME-projektet</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="cs">Projekt GNOME</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="ca">El projecte GNOME</developer_name>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">org.gnome.Contacts.desktop</launchable>
  <translation type="gettext">gnome-contacts</translation>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1">
    <content_attribute id="violence-cartoon">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="violence-fantasy">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="violence-realistic">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="violence-bloodshed">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="violence-sexual">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="violence-desecration">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="violence-slavery">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="violence-worship">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="drugs-alcohol">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="drugs-narcotics">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="drugs-tobacco">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="sex-nudity">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="sex-themes">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="sex-homosexuality">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="sex-prostitution">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="sex-adultery">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="sex-appearance">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="language-profanity">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="language-humor">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="language-discrimination">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="social-chat">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="social-info">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="social-audio">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="social-location">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="social-contacts">intense</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="money-purchasing">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="money-gambling">none</content_attribute>
  </content_rating>
</component>
